## Sue Liu

Edinburgh, UK

Email: yu.sue.liu@cantab.net

Github: https://github.com/yusueliu

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sue-liu-445b06b8

Experienced data science and machine learning professional skilled in leadership, product management and research. Currently leading a team of data scientists and machine learning engineers at UserTesting working on improving its two-sided marketplace. Proficient python programmer with in-depth knowledge of machine learning and practical experience in MLOps, AWS and building microservices. Research interests include Bayesian machine learning, probabilistic programming and NLP.

## Experience

#### **UserTesting**

#### Machine Learning Engineering Manager

Dec 2021 - Present

- Lead an engineering team to build ML products
- Design and build data pipelines and microservices
- Manage a team of machine learning engineers and support stakeholder decision-making

#### Team Lead, Machine Learning Engineering

Jul 2020 - Present

#### Senior Machine Learning Engineer

Dec 2019 - Dec 2021

#### Mudano

### Senior Data Scientist

May 2018 - Dec 2019

Built machine learning features for the project management software Sharktower, including sentiment analysis and project modeller.

#### sensewhere Limited

#### **Computing Research Engineer**

May 2017 - Apr 2018

Conducted machine learning research to solve indoor positioning problems using WiFi and sensor data.

#### The Floow

#### **Data Scientist**

Sep 2016 - May 2017

Built machine learning capabilities in the Floom's scoring and risk prediction models.

#### Post-doctoral Research Scientist

The University of Edinburgh Apr 2013 - Aug 2016

#### Research Fellow in Mathematics

University of St Andrews Oct 2010 - Mar 2013

## Education

### University of Cambridge

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Applied Mathematics 2005 - 2009

### University of Cambridge

MMath, Mathematics 2004 - 2005

### Trinity College, University of Cambridge

BA Mathematics 2001 - 2004

## **Skills**

Leadership, Product and people management
Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Mathematics
Python, SQL, Java
AWS, PostgreSQL, scikit-learn, Tensorflow, PyTorch

# Languages

English, Mandarin (Bilingual), German (Intermediate), Dutch (Beginner)